Guide to the Asian American Arts Centre Records TAM.613
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive
Asian American Arts Centre Records
1960s-2000s
TAM.613
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive
150.0 linear feet in 127 record cartons and 17 oversize flat boxes
Asian American Arts Centre.
Asian American Dance Theatre.
Asian Arts Institute.
Lee, Robert
Yung, Danny, b. 1943
Arrangement
This collection has not been arranged by an archivist.
Immediate Source of Acquisition note
This collection was donated by the Asian American Arts Centre (courtesy of Robert Lee, Eleanor Yung, and Danny Yung) in March 2012. The accession number associated with this gift is 2012.022.
Scope and Content Note
The collection is primarily comprised of the organizational records of the Asian American Arts Centre. It is also contains the files of the Asian American Dance Theatre and the Asian Arts Institute, which merged to form Asian American Arts Center in 1987. Included in the collection are planning materials and publicity for Asian American Arts Centre exhibitions and other programming in the areas of Asian folk arts, international politics (such as the "China - June 4th, 1989" exhibition on the Tiananmen Square protests), and life and events in New York City (such as the exhibitions "Below the Canal After 9/11" and "New York Eviction Blues"). The collection also contains files related to Asian American Arts Centre and Asian American Dance Theatre/Asian Art Institute's grantsmanship, fundraising, and development, including grant proposals, foundation research, end-of-the-year fundraising form letters, etc. Many of the papers are the correspondence and notes of Robert Lee, one of the founders and the Executive Director of Asian American Arts Council, and Eleanor Yung, another Asian Amerian Arts Council founder and the artistic director of the former Asian American Dance Theatre.
To a lesser extent, the collection also includes materials generated by The Association of American Cultures and early Asian American movement organizations like Basement Workshop. The research files of Danny Yung, brother of Eleanor Yung, are also present, as are legal documents from the 26 Bowery case (Robert Lee and Eleanor Yung v. Tien Yick Co., Inc.). Some of the files pertain to Zuni Icosahedron, an experimental theater group from Hong Kong, of which Danny Yung is the artistic director.
Access Restrictions
Boxes which contain personnel, programming, and development materials with Social Security numbers are currently closed to researchers. All other materials are open for research without restrictions.
Separated Materials
Forty-four linear feet of art books, catalogues, and serials from the collection were given to the Institute of Fine Arts at New York University. An additional four linear feet of books and serials were separated for cataloging by the Tamiment Library. Duplicates of flyers, programs, and other printed ephemera were removed. Some personal materials were separated and may be returned to the donors.
Historical/Biographical Note
The Asian American Arts Centre, founded in 1974 as Asian American Dance Theatre, is one of the older community arts organizations in New York City Chinatown. The current name, Asian American Arts Centre, was adopted in 1987 to encompass both the dance company (Asian American Dance Theatre) and the visual arts program, Asian Arts Institute, initiated in 1984.
The Asian American Arts Centre began the Asian American Artists’ Slide Archive in 1982. Artist vertical files were developed and accumulated as a permanent research archive documenting the history of Asian/Pacific American Artists in the United States since 1945 to the present. The archive contains not only slides but also a variety of materials that are both primary and secondary sources from approximately 1,500 artists.
In 1986, the Asian American Art Centre initiated a research project with the support of the Rockefeller Foundation called the "Milieu" series. The project focused on Asian American artists from the post World War era (1945 to1965), contextualized them and their artwork within this historical setting, and provided a historical precedent for the cultural presence of young Asian American artists. About ninety artists who began their career between 1945 to 1965 were selected and extensive research was conducted for many of them, resulting in extensive documents and materials in their files. Some were interviewed in their native language and documentation from these interviews has also been archived.
In 2007, the Asian American Art Centre created a new archive, the AAAC Artist Archive, from a part of the original slide archive as part of its digitization project. 150 artists who exemplified the major issues that compose the subject of Asian American art were selected and their materials processed for long-term archival preservation. Selected materials from these 150 artists were in turn digitized and made available on the website http://artasiamerica.org. The centre’s creation of and commitment to preserve and make accessible its Artist Archive is part of the organization’s greater mission to “promote the preservation and creative vitality of Asian American cultural growth through the arts, and its historical and aesthetic linkage to other communities.”
Asian American Arts Alliance.; Asian American Arts Centre.; Asian American Dance Theatre.; Asian Arts Institute.; Association of American Cultures.; Basement Workshop.; Chin, Rockwell (Rocky); Lee, Robert; Yung, Danny, b. 1943; Yung, Eleanor; Art |x Political aspects.; Asian American art.; Asian Americans |x Civil rights.; Asian Americans.; Community organization |z New York (State) |z New York.; Folk art.; New York (N.Y.)
- Asian-Pacific American Community Research, late 1970s-mid 2000s (Box 1)
- Oversize Box: Publications, Masks, Hat, 1990s (Box 2)
- Program Files and Personnel Files, 1980s-2000s (Box 3)
- Budgets and Financial Records, late 1980s-2000s (Box 4)
  Access Restrictions
  This box contains Social Security numbers and is therefore closed to researchers.
- Legal Files, 1980s-2000s (Box 5)
  This box contains student work and may contain confidential information like Social Security numbers and is therefore closed to researchers.
- Program Files and Personnel Files, 1990s (Box 6)
  This box contains Social Security numbers and therefore is currently closed to researchers.
- Program Files and Personnel Files, 1980s-1990s (Box 7)
- Program Files and Personnel Files, late 1980s-2000s (Box 8)
- Program Files and Personnel Files, 1990s-2000s (Box 9)
- Budgets and Financial Records, 1990s-2000s (Box 10)
  This box contains Social Security numbers and is therefore currently closed to researchers.
- Budgets and Financial Records, 1980s-2000s (Box 11)
- Program Files and Personnel Files, 1970s-2000s (Box 12)
  Photographic materials in this box are in need of rehousing and are currently closed to researchers.
- Program Files and Personnel Files, 1980s-2000s (Box 13)
- Program Files and Personnel Files, 1980s-1990s (Box 14)
- Program Files and Personnel Files, 1990s-2000s (Box 15)
- Program Files and Personnel Files, 1980s-2000s (Box 16)
- Audio and Video Recordings of performances, 1980s-2000s (Box 17)
- Audio and Video Recordings of performances, 1980s-2000s (Box 18)
- Audio and Video Recordings of performances, 1990s-2000s (Box 19)
- Budgets and Financial Records, 1980s-1990s (Box 20)
- Program Files and Personnel Files, 1978-2009 (Box 21)
- Budgets and Financial Records, 1980s, 2000s (Box 22)
- Budgets and Financial Records, 1980s-2000s (Box 23)
- "China - June 4, 1989" Exhibit, late 1980s-2000s (Box 24)
- Budgets and Financial Records, 1970s-1990s (Box 25)
- Serials and Printed Ephemera, 1980s-1990s (Box 26)
- Serials and Printed Ephemera, 1980s-1990s (Box 27)
- Executive Director and Board of Directors Files, 1980s-1990s (Box 28)
- Serials and Printed Ephemera, 1980s-1990s (Box 29)
- Program Files and Personnel Files, 1980s-1990s (Box 30)
- Audio and Video Recordings of performances, 1980s-2000s (Box 31)
- Audio and Video Recordings of performances, 1980s-1990s (Box 32)
- Audio and Video Recordings of performances, 1977-1996 (Box 33)
- Legal Files, 1980s-2000s (Box 34)
- Serials and Printed Ephemera, 1980s-2000s (Box 35)
- Audio and Video Recordings of performances, 1974-early 1990s (Box 36)
- Audio and Video Recordings of performances, circa 1990-1999 (Box 37)
- Program Files and Personnel Files, 1980s-1990s (Box 38)
- Program Files and Personnel Files, 1980s-1990s (Box 39)
- Executive Director and Board of Directors Files, 1980s (Box 40)
- Oversize Box: Words on Cardboard (from box originally labeled "Old Papers + Mail Bob Personal 1984"), Guestbook (Box 41)
- Audio and Video Recordings of performances, circa 1980-1989 (Box 42)
- Executive Director and Board of Directors Files, 1980s-1990s (Box 43)
- Budgets and Financial Records, 1980s (Box 44)
- Executive Director and Board of Directors Files, 1990s (Box 45)
- Executive Director and Board of Directors Files, 1980s-1990s (Box 46)
- Program Files and Personnel Files, 1980s-1990s (Box 47)
- Budgets and Financial Records, 1980s-1990s (Box 48)
- Program Files and Personnel Files, 1980s-1990s (Box 49)
- Executive Director and Board of Directors Files, late 1980s-early 1990s (Box 50)
- Executive Director and Board of Directors Files, 1980s (Box 51)
- Executive Director and Board of Directors Files, 1980s-2000s (Box 52)
- Program Files and Personnel Files, 1980s-1990s (Box 53)
- Audio and Video Recordings of performances, late 1980s-2002 (Box 54)
- Budgets and Financial Records, late 1980s-2000s (Box 55)
- Program Files and Personnel Files, late 1980s-early 2000s (Box 56)
- Program Files and Personnel Files, 1990s (Box 57)
- Executive Director and Board of Directors Files, 1970s-2000s (Box 58)
- Asian-Pacific American Community Research, 1980s-early 2000s (Box 59)
- Program Files and Personnel Files, 1980s-early 2000s (Box 60)
- Program Files and Personnel Files, 1985-2000 (Box 61)
- Program Files and Personnel Files, 1970s-1980s (Box 62)
- Program Files and Personnel Files, 1987-2006 (Box 63)
- Asian-Pacific American Community Research, mid 1980s-2003 (Box 64)
- Program Files and Personnel Files, early 1990s (Box 65)
- Executive Director and Board of Directors Files, 1990s-early 2000s (Box 66)
- Program Files and Personnel Files, 1980s-2007 (Box 67)
- Program Files and Personnel Files, late 1980s-2000s (Box 68)
- "China - June 4, 1989" Exhibit, 1980s-1990s (Box 69)
- Audio and Video Recordings of performances, 1970s-1990s (Box 70)
- Audio and Video Recordings of performances, late 1980s-circa early 2000s (Box 71)
- Audio and Video Recordings of performances, 1990-2003 (Box 72)
- Audio and Video Recordings of performances, 1988-2000 (Box 73)
- Audio and Video Recordings of performances, 1980s-early 2000s (Box 74)
- Asian American Arts Center Original Archive Index Cards, 1980s? (Box 75)
- Program Files and Personnel Files, 1980s-1990s (Box 76)
- "China - June 4, 1989" Exhibit, 1975, 1980s-1990s (Box 77)
- Program Files and Personnel Files, late 1980s-2009 (Box 78)
- Program Files and Personnel Files, 1980s-early 2000s (Box 79)
- Budgets and Financial Records, 1980s, 2000s (Box 80)
- Development Files, 2000s (Box 81)
- Development Files, 1990s-2000s (Box 82)
- Program Files and Personnel Files, circa 1977-2009 (Box 83)
- Program Files and Personnel Files, 1980s, 2000s (Box 84)
- Program Files and Personnel Files, 1980s-2000s (Box 85)
- Program Files and Personnel Files, 1980s (Box 86)
- Program Files and Personnel Files, late 1980s, 2000s (Box 87)
- "China - June 4, 1989" Exhibit, late 1980s-1990s (Box 88)
- Program Files and Personnel Files, late 1980s-2011 (Box 89)
- Serials and Printed Ephemera, 1980s-2000s (Box 90)
- Budgets and Financial Records, 1970s-1980s, 2000s (Box 91)
- Serials and Printed Ephemera, 1970s-1980s (Box 92)
- Executive Director and Board of Directors Files, 1980s-2000s (Box 93)
- Executive Director and Board of Directors Files, 1970s-2000s (Box 94)
- Executive Director and Board of Directors Files, 1969, 1980s-2000s (Box 95)
- Program Files and Personnel Files, 1970s, 1990s-2000s (Box 96)
- Asian-Pacific American Community Research, 1970s (Box 97)
- Asian-Pacific American Community Research, 1970s (possibly some late 1960s) (Box 98)
- Audio and Video Recordings of performances, circa 1980-1999 (Box 99)
- Slides, circa 1982-1991 (Box 100)
- Serials and Printed Ephemera, 1989-2000s (Box 101)
- Serials and Printed Ephemera, 1970s-2000s (Box 102)
- Executive Director and Board of Directors Files, 1980s-1990s (Box 103)
- Asian-Pacific American Community Research, 1960s-1970s (Box 104)
- Asian-Pacific American Community Research, 1970s (possibly late 1960s) (Box 105)
- Asian-Pacific American Community Research, 1960s-1970s (Box 106)
- Asian-Pacific American Community Research, 1960s-1970s (Box 107)
- Serials and Printed Ephemera, 1960s-2000s (Box 108)
- Executive Director and Board of Directors Files, 1980s-1990s (Box 109)
- Executive Director and Board of Directors Files, 1980s-1990s (Box 110)
- Serials and Printed Ephemera, 1980s-1990s (Box 111)
- Audio and Video Recordings of performances, circa 1980-1989 (Box 112)
- Program Files and Personnel Files, 1979-2000s (Box 113)
- Program Files and Personnel Files, 1980s-1990s (Box 114)
- Program Files and Personnel Files, 1990s (Box 115)
- Program Files and Personnel Files, 1980s-1990s (Box 116)
- Executive Director and Board of Directors Files, 1980s-1990s (Box 117)
- Asian-Pacific American Community Research, 1960s-1970s (Box 118)
- Program Files and Personnel Files, 1980s-1990s (Box 119)
- Program Files and Personnel Files, 1980s-1990s (Box 120)
- Program Files and Personnel Files, 1980s (Box 121)
- Program Files and Personnel Files, 1980s-1990s (Box 122)
- Program Files and Personnel Files, 1980s-1990s (Box 123)
- Serials and Printed Ephemera, 1980s-1990s (Box 124)
- Audio and Video Recordings of performances, circa 1980-1989 (Box 125)
- Program Files and Personnel Files, 1990s (Box 126)
- Legal Files, 1980s (Box 127)
- Legal Files, 1980s-1990s (Box 128)
- Program Files and Personnel Files, 1970s-1990s (Box 129)
- "China - June 4, 1989" Exhibit, late 1980s-early 1990s (Box 130-144)